{
    "id": "c58d3a249dfd444dbe59e386d86e8173",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Push the button ……………………. you want the elevator.",
            "description": "If expresses a condition. ",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "in case of",
                "whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The prostrate slaves didn’t get up ………………………… the king left.",
            "description": "Until refers to time. Up to refers to distance or extent. ",
            "answers": [
                "until",
                "up to",
                "as far as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He was a proud man ………………………. resisted his friends’ offers of help.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun who refers to people. It acts as the subject of the verb in the relative clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "His rapacious ways made him wealthy ……………………….. friendless.",
            "description": "But is used to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "but",
                "or"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He rarely studied, ………………………. he passed every exam.",
            "description": "Yet is used to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "yet",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The witness related ……………………….. he had seen.",
            "description": "What means that which.",
            "answers": [
                "what",
                "that",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It stormed ……………………. hard that all the electricity went out.",
            "description": "So...that shows cause and effect.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "very",
                "too"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He is so tight-lipped that no one knew ………………………. he enjoyed the party or not.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "that",
                "if"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The best tactic is to confess ………………………. ask her forgiveness.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "so",
                "or"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The child is unruly ……………………….. he has been spoiled.",
            "description": "Because gives the reason.",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "because",
                "hence"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The two men look alike ……………………….. are unrelated.",
            "description": "But is used to connect two contrasting ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "as",
                "but"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She didn’t understand ……………………. was happening to her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "what",
                "that",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}